格林 前情提要
Previously on Grimm.
他们自称格物生物
They call themselves Wesen.
相信我 他们真实存在
Believe me, they're out there.
- 你看得到他们  - 当他们发怒的时候
- and you see them all the time -only when they are upset and pissed off
他们知道你是格林的后代吗
Do they all know you're one of these Grimms?
我觉得他们能感觉到 能认出我
I think they can sense it and recognize them.
一开始 他们就要谋害他
From the beginning, they've conspired by against him.
Nick 从我这里夺走一些东西
Nick took something away from me,
所以其人之道还至其人之身
so I took something away from him.
她陷入昏迷
She's in a coma.
他们把她从他身边夺走
They've taken from him.
- 失去你我也不活了  - 你是谁
- I love you so much. - Who are you?
这不奇怪吗
Doesn't it seem strange that
Juliette就不记得你是谁
the only thing Juliette doesn't remember is you?
也许这就是Adalind所计划的
Maybe that was Adalind's plan all along.
但是他们还是没有获得最重要的东西
But they yet to get what matters most.
保管好这个 用生命去守护它
Never lose this. Guard it with your life.
是警监把Juliette救醒的
The captain is the one who woke Juliette up.
是他救了你
He saved your life.
你想要我做什么
What do you want from me?
如果抛开彼此成见 我们可以干一番大事业
If you and I can overcome our differences, we will make history.
- 你相信他  - 我不知道
- You trust him? - I don't know.
Juliette记得关于拖车的事情
Juliette remembered seeing you in the trailer.
你认为我的记忆正在恢复吗
You think my memory is coming back?
汝命殁于此 吾于林中孤身静默 弃之
你从十三世纪的君士坦丁堡里
What did you take from Constantinople
拿了什么重要的东西
in the 13th century that was so damn important?
你到底埋了什么东西
What the hell did you bury?
见鬼
Damn.
我操
What the hell?
不是吧
Are you kidding me?
John
John?
哦 苍天 哦 佛祖
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
重要的是 我老爸非常的传统 好吗
Bottom line, my dad was very old-school, okay?
- 是非一般的传统  - 你老爸还在打猎
- I mean, very old-school. - Your dad still hunts?
不了
No.
好吧 让我换种方式和你说
Well, let me put it this way.
我不问 他也知道最好不要和我说这个
I don't ask and he knows better than to talk to me about it.
但是晚餐不会自己上门
But they're not getting any meals on wheels,
我就只说这么多
I'll tell you that much.
那你母亲呢
What about your mom?
再次申明 我不是很清楚
Well, again, I don't know for sure,
但是她不会让他一个人在外面瞎晃荡的
but she doesn't let him go anywhere by himself.
特别是晚上 因为他找不到
Especially at night, because he's not also great
回家的路
about finding his way home.
他们还住在你小时候住的房子吗
Do they still live in the same house you grew up in?
是滴 半月湖 新罕布什尔州
They do. Half moon lake, New Hampshire.
原来的镇 原来的街
Same town, same street.
原来的那个配有三居室肮脏简陋像狼窝的小房子
Same three-bedroom with a large, kind of den house
房屋后面就是国家森林 懂吗
that backs up against the state forest, you know?
方便进出
For easy access.
但是问题是 他们  他们想我
But the problem is, really, they just... they miss me
想出来与子同乐几周
and they want to come out and spend a couple of weeks.
这有什么问题
What's wrong with that, huh?
没事 只是他们从没有住过酒店
Nothing. It's just, they never stay in a hotel.
他们想我和住一起 你知道现在有点不方便
They always stay here and right now it's kind of awkward,
因为
because...
是的 Nick要和你爸妈共处一室
oh, right. Nick and your parents under the same roof.
是啊 这就是问题所在
Yeah, that would be a problem.
是滴 我的意思是说 主要是
Yeah, I mean, bottom line,
我不想Nick把我父母给杀了
I don't want Nick to kill my parents.
并不是说 他们不会给他很多理由去做这件事
Not that they wouldn't give him plenty of reasons.
我相信Nick会理解的 好吗
I bet Nick would understand, right?
只是当你爸妈来的时候让他搬出去一阵子
Just move out while they're here?
他可以和Hank住一段时间 或者和我
He could stay with Hank or even me.
是啊 可能吧
Yeah, maybe.
就目前形势来看
It's just that the way things are going right now,
我不认为 没有我的帮助 Nick可以撑下去
I'm not sure Nick could do without my help for that long.
他有说起过Juliette吗
Has he said anything about Juliette?
米有 但是 在我看来
No, not much, but it doesn't look to me
短时间内他俩呆不到一块去
like they're gonna be getting together anytime soon.
嘿 谁知道呢 情侣之间的关系总是变化莫测的
Well, hey, you never know. Relationships are unpredictable.
Monroe 你在楼上吗
Monroe, you up?
嗨 Monroe 你在家吗 我需要你的帮助
Hey, Monroe! You home? I need your help!
喔 你们在这呢 嗨  Rosalee
Oh, there you are. Hi, Rosalee.
你好
Hello.
我打扰到你们了吗
Um, this is me intruding, isn't it?
我现在就回房
I'm going to my room now.
- 等下 Nick 如果你需要Monroe的  - 不 不
- Nick, wait, if you need Monroe's... - No, no.
不急 不急着说
No. This can wait.
- 喔  - 懂我的意思了吧
- Oh. - See what I mean?
我想你是对的
I think you're right.
让你父母现在过来
It's probably not the best idea
可能不是个好主意
to have your parents come out right now.
我们明天晚上继续这事吧
Why don't we try this again tomorrow night?
- 在我那  - 一定到
- At my place. -I'll be there.
说吧 虾米事情
So... Problem?
对不起 Monroe
Sorry, Monroe.
但是你俩发展得挺顺利的
But it looks like things are going really well with you two.
是滴 火花四射啊
Yeah. I mean, they're actually going amazing.
所以某时候一些小小的打扰
So one little interruption at just the right moment,
不会是世界末日
not gonna be the end of the world.
你有什么发现
What do you got?
- 我姨妈把这个给我了  - 这是什么
- My aunt gave me this. - What is that?
我猜想 这把钥匙是解开
Supposedly it's one of the keys that locked away
某件重要事情的关键
something very important.
天哪 这把钥匙可是个老古董了
Oh, man. This is really old.
如果你用墨水把钥匙的俩面都拓下来，可以拼成一幅地图
You ink the sides of it... And it makes the piece of a map.
我妈妈告诉我有6把这样的钥匙 而且
My mom told me there are six more of those and that...
嘿 哥话还没说完呢
hey!
Monroe 你去哪
Monroe, where are you going?
我想我知道这个 Nick 我知道这个
I think I know this, Nick. I think I know this.
- 钥匙吗 真的  - 不是 地图
- The key? Seriously? - No, the map.
但是这个钥匙很古老了
But the key is very old.
可能要追溯到中世纪时期了
I'd say made sometime during the middle ages.
这些东西最早是在修道院里才用到的
You know, a lot of them were first designed in monasteries.
这个叫做巫师锁 我不是和你说那种男巫师
It's called a ward-lock, and I'm not talking about a male witch.
而是 他们合用一套巫术的东西 把它称为巫师锁
It's a... they use a set of obstructions called wards.
但是我现在对这张地图更感兴趣
But I'm really more interested in the map right now.
好吧
Okay.
这是一张Schwaben的老地图
This is an ancient map of Schwaben,
现在叫做斯瓦比亚 在德国巴伐利亚州境内
which is Swabia, which is in Bavaria.
你看这两张地图多么相似啊
You see the similarities between this map and yours?
你怎么知道这些东西的
How do you know all this stuff?
我曾曾曾外祖父
Well, my great-great-great- grandfather on my mother's side
在Colmar是一名制图者 是法国东部 洛林的阿尔萨斯
was a cartographer in Colmar, which is in Alsace Lorraine,
就在黑森林附近
which is basically right across from the black forest.
说正题
Anyway.
正题 当德国吞并Colmar 我从他那里继承了很多
Anyway, I inherited a ton of his stuff that wasn't burned
在法国和普鲁士战争中没有烧掉的东西
during the Franco-prussian war when Germany annexed Colmar.
我猜想 你的这张地图的制图风格是走的Behaim路线
My guess, this map of yours was drawn in the Behaim style,
可能正好是Schwarzwald (德语中黑森林的说法) 中的一部分
which could put it squarely in the Schwarzwald.
对不起 黑森林
Sorry, the black forest.
你看 山峰排列的方式 还有水流路径
See? The way the hills and the waterways are drawn...
我想说的是 以前的地图也就只能画成这样了
I mean, this is before they could be all that accurate.
所以你是说 这一小块地图
So you're telling me from this little piece of map,
是德国的某个地方
you think it's somewhere in Germany?
是滴
Oh, yeah.
我以我曾曾曾外祖父的名义起誓
I'd bet my great-great-great- grandfather on it.
这张地图是用来干什么的
What's the map for, anyway?
可能是13世纪的十字军洗劫君士坦丁堡的时候
It's supposedly crusaders in the 13th century
发现的某样东西
sacked Constantinople, and they found something
而这东西力量太强大了
that they considered too powerful to return
他们不想把它带给那些资助他们东征的贵族
to the royal families who helped finance their crusade.
而且他们有7个人 都是格林后裔
And there were seven of them and they were all Grimms.
他们一定洗劫了非常重要的东西
They must have sacked something pretty significant.
知道是虾米吗
Any idea what?
没人知道
Nobody seems to know.
但是很多人想找到它
But a lot of people want to find out
不惜杀人也要得到它
and they're willing to kill for it.
好吧
Okay.
谁有其他六把钥匙
So who has the other six keys?
我不知道
I don't know for sure.
但是有人可能知道
But there's someone who might.
我带你去的 Nick
I took you, Nick.
我带你去David和Ron家聚会的 但是
I took you to that party at David and Roni's, but...
亲吻之前我们在干什么呢
what were we doing before we kissed?
- Juliette  - 你好
- Juliette. - Hey.
- 你看上去心情不好  - 真的吗 很明显吗
- You don't look very happy. - Really? Does it show?
是的 有点
Yeah, a little.
因为Nick吗
Is it Nick trouble?
不 和他毫无关系
No, not even.
是我自己 是我自己的问题
It's ridiculous. I'm being ridiculous.
一切都好 我 我们俩进展很顺利
Everything is so good, I'm... we're going great.
我们都非常适合对方
We're just so perfect for each other
但是我们还没有涉及到这个话题
but nobody has said how they feel yet.
噢 你是说你们还没有正式表白
Ohh, you mean in terms of the word "Love."
我可没这么说
I did not say that.
我 我要去续杯
I'm... l'm gonna get a refill.
等会回来
Be right back.
- 嗨 Nick  - 嗨 Roni
- Hi, Nick. - Hi, Roni.
- 嘿  - 你朋友很友善
- Hey. - Your friends are really nice.
太好了 我很高兴你喜欢这里
Good, I'm glad you're having a good time.
我很喜欢
I am...
和你在一起
With you.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
因为这个传统嘛
Tradition.
我刚把气氛搞坏了
I just ruined the moment.
不 不 你没有
No. No, you didn't.
我是想告诉你 我爱你
I'm trying to tell you that I love you.
很好 因为我也爱你
Well, that's good because I love you too.
大家 看这里
Hey, guys.
谢天谢地 你回来了
Thank God you're back.
快点给我
Give it to me.
- 亲爱的  - 嗯
- Baby. - Mm!
亲爱的 慢点吃
Baby, slow down.
你会噎着的
You're gonna choke.
哦 天啦 你受伤了
Oh, no, you hurt yourself.
我很好 别担心
I'm fine. Don't worry about it.
- 你感觉如何  - 好多了
- How are you feeling? - Better.
孩子在踢我 你摸摸看
The baby's kicking. You want to feel?
太美妙了
That's nice.
你要休息下
You gotta get some rest.
我们明天早上就要离开这里
We have to move in the morning again.
天哪
Oh, God.
我快受不了了
I can't do this much longer.
我以为我们在这里很安全
I thought we were safe here.
我原先也是这样认为的
I did too.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Bell Crossing路的Hadley农场
We have an update on the attack at Hadley ranch,
发生一起遇袭案件
Bell crossing road.
已确认一人死亡
Confirmation of one person killed,
畜牧被肢解
livestock mutilated.
法医已经到场了
Medical staging.
农场主称是外星人侵袭
Rancher claims attack was from an alien,
不是违法分子袭击
and not the illegal kind.
小心处理 可能有精神方面的问题
Proceed with caution, potential mental health issues.
糟糕
Damn it.
- 我们有麻烦了  - 什么
- We've got a problem. - What?
车发动不起来
The car won't start.
可能是电瓶或者启动器坏了 我不确定
It's either the battery or the starter, I'm not sure.
-那我们怎么办  -你得呆在这儿
- Well, what are we gonna do? - You're gonna stay here,
休息一会儿
keep off your feet.
我去再找一辆车
I'm going to get us another car.
不要离开我
I don't want you to leave me.
宝贝 我也不想走
Baby, I don't want to go either,
但我们别无选择
but we don't have a choice.
我爱你
I love you.
我们会没事的
We're gonna make it.
- 我有错过什么事吗  - 算是吧
- Am I late for something? - In a way.
就是说这次和案子无关咯
I take it this is not about a case?
这次是有关一把钥匙的事
We're talking about a key.
现在说来听听也行
I suppose now is as good a time as any.
我知道有7把钥匙
I know there's seven keys.
我知道它们指向一些在13世纪就被埋藏起来
I know they lead to something that was buried
的事情
in the 13th century.
那你知道是什么事吗
Do you know what it is?
我所知道的是
What I know is this.
皇室家族现在已经掌握了其中的4把
The royal families have four of the seven keys.
你有一把
You hold one.
这意味着有两把钥匙仍然下落不明
That means there are still two that are unaccounted for.
当7把钥匙的图案
Now when the maps of all seven keys
被拼凑起来 我们就能知道
are put together, the location of what it is they buried
他们埋藏物品的具体地点
will be known.
那七位十字军决定欺骗皇室
Those seven crusaders who took it upon themselves
他们是你的先辈
to deceive the royal families, they were your ancestors.
然而 其中有一个背叛了其它六人
However, one of the seven would betray the other six.
他这么做 是因为他受尽了折磨
He did so, mind you, only after severe torture.
所以你的祖先折磨了我的祖先
So your ancestors tortured one of mine
来取得钥匙
to get his key.
那他们怎么得到其余三把的
How'd they get the other three?
怎么说呢 整个过程 以我们现在的标准来看
Well, let me just say there was a lot of bloodshed.
也非常的血腥
Even by our standards.
不过 他们仍然花了600年才取得那三把钥匙
Still, it took 600 years to get three more keys.
那他们为什么要付出这么大的代价
So what's worth all that?
那取决于你相信哪一个神话
Well, that all depends on which legend you believe.
在一个版本中 那里藏着炼金术的秘密
In one, it's the secret of alchemy.
另一个则是长生不老的秘诀
In another, everlasting life.
还有第三种说法 说那里有先知穆罕默德的剑
A third has it associated with the prophet Mohammed's sword,
那剑似乎拥有强大的力量
which apparently holds a great deal of power.
最后一种 说那里有把耶稣钉在十字架上的钉子
And lastly, the nails that secured Christ to the cross,
可能还有部分十字架的残片
and possibly some of those pieces of the cross itself.
据说也有极大的力量
They are said to hold immense power too.
我们要信这个吗
Do we believe this?
那七名十字军觉得他们所发现的东西
Seven crusaders felt it was worth their lives
值得用生命来守护 以确保不会落入坏人之手
not to have what they found fall into the wrong hands.
他们一定找到了足以说服他们自己的东西
I guess they found something that convinced them.
所以现在问题就变成
So the question for us would be,
我们能不相信他们吗
can we afford not to believe them?
也许不行
Maybe not.
但我们要怎么做
But what are we gonna do about it?
目前来说 确保我家人
Well, for now, make sure to keep my family's hands
不去碰你那把钥匙
off your key.
我想你和你家人的关系并不是那么好
So I guess you and your family aren't all that close.
按你的说法 我的家庭
My family, as you call them,
可能更希望我没出生
would have been happier had I never been born.
这么说吧 如果我不去招惹他们
Let me just say that if I stay out of their way,
他们也不会来管我
they leave me be.
不过他们也 偶尔 想把我干掉
Not that they haven't tried to kill me on occasion.
那你就准备离他们远远的吗
Do you plan to stay out of their way?
这一定程度上取决于你
Well, part of that depends on you.
为啥
How?
你信任我吗
Do you trust me?
大概和你信任我的程度一样
Probably about as much as you trust me.
请进
Yeah?
抱歉打扰了 不过我们接到了一个奇怪的案件
Sorry to interrupt, but we have a weird one.
有点超出了我们的管辖范围
A little out of our jurisdiction,
但郡上要求我们的协助
but county's requesting assistance.
是什么事
What is it?
牛遭到肢解 可能还有谋杀
Cattle mutilations, possible homicide.
有意思的是
And here's the fun part.
根据牧场的人描述
The perp, according to the rancher?
罪犯是个外星人
He's an alien life form.
真相等着我们去挖掘
The truth is out there...
波特兰东部
East of Portland.
我们随时可以出发
Ready when you are.
这就是事发地点
This is where it happened.
当我看见John的时候 我知道情况不妙
When I saw John, I knew it was bad.
我只能祈祷他不要死
I just hoped to hell he wasn't gonna die.
我试着把他弄上我的车
I tried to put him on the atv with me and...
- 我是Doug Parcell  - Burkhardt 侦探
- I'm Doug Parcell. - Detective Burkhardt.
- 吴警官  - 你好
- Sergeant Wu. - Hi.
这是我们的兽医 Kevin Levalle
That's our county vet, Kevin Levalle.
午夜刚过我就来到了这里
I got out here to the ranch a little after midnight.
医护人员对John已经无能为力
Paramedics couldn't do anything about John.
车上有血迹
There's blood on the atv.
看来他遭受了严重的撞击
Seems to me he must have been hit pretty hard,
被推倒在栅栏柱上了
got pushed back into his own fencepost,
背部穿透
pierced his back.
他杀了我的六头牛 还杀了John
He killed six of my cows and he killed John.
我对天发誓
Now, I swear to God,
我不知道那是个什么鬼东西
I don't know what the hell it was.
我以前从没见过
I never saw anything like it before,
但他看起来很像外星生物
but it was some kind of alien being.
他会发光
He was glowing.
然后我看他往那边跑了
And then I saw him run off that way.
昨晚他也是这么和我说的
Same thing he told me last night.
我在想是不是有人穿了某种聚酯薄膜外套
I'm wondering if it's a guy in some kind of mylar coat.
我说的是 他在发光
I'm telling you, he was glowing.
我知道这听起来很不靠谱 但实在
I know how that sounds, but there's no other way
没有别的办法来形容他
to describe it.
这些动物都是他杀的吗
He do this to all your animals?
嗯 开膛破肚了
Yeah. Cut them open.
但不是为了牛肉
But he didn't do it for the meat.
他说的对 没有屠宰迹象
He's right, there was no butchering.
这肯定是某种仪式
It must have been some kind of cult ritual thing.
不 他肯定不是地球上的生物
No. What I saw wasn't from this earth.
如果他往那里跑的话 他会跑到什么地方
What's he run into if he runs that direction?
我的栅栏从这一直延伸至0.75英里远
My fence line is about 3/4 of a mile from here.
- 我们能借用下你的卡车吗  - 尽管用
- Mind if we borrow your truck? - No, no. Go ahead.
好吧 我想我知道他从哪出去的了
Well, I think we know where he got out.
不是很优雅嘛 肯定很疼
Not very gracefully. That had to hurt.
看起来有点像蜥蜴的皮
Looks sort of like lizard skin.
那得是一只多大的蜥蜴啊
That'd be a damn big lizard.
我很感激你们所做的事
Well, I appreciate everything you fellas are doing.
一旦有进展 我们会打电话通知你
We'll call you as soon as we learn anything.
我只是希望你们能找到元凶 不管他是谁
I just hope you find whatever it was that did this.
这就是Hadley牧场吗
This is the Hadley ranch.
这就是事发地点 对吗
This is where it happened, right?
- 你就是Hadley  - 不是
- Are you Hadley? - No.
那你们一定是在调查这起外星人袭击事件了
So you must be looking into the alien attack.
呃 先生 这是警方调查
Uh, sir, this is a police investigation.
我懂 我懂
Oh, I know, I know.
我不会妨碍你们调查的
I'm not trying to get in the way.
我只是来帮忙的
I'm just trying to help out here.
比如 你们知不知道
For instance, did you know that these attacks
现在全国已经发生了多起类似事件
have been happening all across the country?
好吧 来 这是我的名片
Well, here, let me give you my card.
George Lazure 外星人猎手 或者 叫我UFO学家也行
George Lazure, alien hunter. Or if you prefer, ufologist.
听着 伙计 你们有拍到照片吗
Listen, guys, did anyone get pictures?
我能出很多钱来买外星人的照片
'Cause I can pay big for an alien photo.
黑白的 彩色的
- - Black and white, color,
都没问题 数码的最好
doesn't matter, but digital's best.
我可以和你们分成的
I'm willing to split with you guys.
- 没有照片 抱歉  - 该死
- No photos, sorry. - Oh, damn.
嘿 你们可以对我直接一点
Hey, look, you can level with me.
我们都是同一战线的 真的 保护民众什么的
We're all on the same team, really, protecting the people.
探测过受害者了吗
Was the victim probed?
没有人被探测过
Nobody was probed...
暂时
Yet.
*No, I gotta know*
*If she'll stick around*
*When the time comes. Oh!*
*To put my truck down*
*Then further up the road*
*We'll park our home*
这里有蓝色的 灰色的
You got your blues, and your greys,
还有来自仙女座的爬虫
and your reptilians, from Andromeda.
那个 我看见的就是他
That one. That's what I saw.
你做了什么
What have you done?
我不想让她认出我
I didn't want her to be able to identify me.
她没事 只是昏过去了
She's all right, she's just passed out.
她可能经历了心脏病突发
She might have had a heart attack.
那我们需要一辆车
Well, we needed a car.
我不知道还有什么办法能弄到车
And I didn't know how else to get one.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
你准备把她就丢在这儿吗
You're just gonna leave her here?
她会没事的
She's gonna be fine.
听着 现在我们得考虑你和你的宝宝
Look, we need to think about you and the baby now.
我们办不到的
We're not gonna make it.
嘿 嘿 我们可以做到
Hey, hey... Yes, we are.
好吗 为了宝宝 你要坚强起来
Okay, you gotta be strong for the baby.
- 这肯定是块皮肤  - 人类的皮肤
- It's definitely skin. - Human skin.
不完全是
Well, not precisely.
如果不是因为刚才停电
You know, I don't know if I would have even seen this
我不确定我是否能看见这个东西
if we hadn't had a power outage.
把灯关掉 我来告诉你是怎么回事
Turn off the lights and I'll show you what I mean.
- 很可爱吧  - 这是啥东西
Pretty, huh? What is it?
萤光素酵素 (拼写与路西法近似)
Luciferase.
你最好能告诉我这东西和魔鬼没关系
Please tell me that has nothing to do with the devil.
这是种掌管生物发光的酵素
It's the enzyme responsible for bio-luminescence.
就像萤火虫那样
Like fireflies.
在很多鱼和海生无脊椎动物里也有发现
Also found in many fish and marine invertebrates.
我们找到它的时候 它并不发光
It wasn't glowing when we found it.
在动物焦躁不安的时候 这种酵素往往会激活
The enzyme usually activates when the animal is agitated.
是一种古老的受压反应
The old fight or flight response.
那么 他到底是动物还是人类
So is it animal or is it human?
不知道
I don't know.
这是块拥有动物皮肤反应的人类皮肤
It's human skin with an animal skin response.
Burkhardt
Burkhardt.
刚刚接到郡治安官的电话
Just got a call from the county sheriff.
看起来我们有另一位目击者了
Apparently we have another witness.
他报案称被外星人绑架了
This one's claiming alien abduction.
所以我们说的是宇宙飞船吗
So are we talking spaceship?
不 是辆野马
No. Bronco.
抱歉 宝贝 我们必须继续走小路
I'm sorry, honey, we gotta stay on the back roads.
你还好吗
You all right?
不 你得靠边停车
No! You have to pull over.
我们得开远一点 我们才走了没多远
We gotta make more Miles, we haven't gone that far.
我需要你停车 有些事情不对劲
I need you to stop, something is wrong.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
- 我能做什么  - 我需要休息
- What can I do? - I need to rest.
我得休息一会儿
I need to rest for a while.
宝贝 你刚才说什么不对劲来着
Babe, you said something was wrong.
如果我不休息 宝宝现在
If I don't rest, I'm gonna have this baby
就会在这儿出生了
right here and now.
那里有间老木屋
There's an old cabin over there.
我有主意了
I've got an idea.
看起来没人在家的样子
Doesn't look like there's anybody home.
我过去看看
I'm gonna check it out.
就要到了 坚持住 坚持住 坚持住
That's it, hold on. Hold on, hold on.
我觉得这里已经很久没人来过了
I don't think anybody's been here for a long time.
好的
Okay.
我们在这歇息一会儿
We'll rest here for a while.
我得去把车藏起来
I'm gonna go hide the car.
Vincent
Vincent...
我又饿了
I'm getting hungry again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不 不 不 嘿 没关系的
No, no, no. Hey, it's okay.
没关系的 我知道
It's okay. I know.
呃 我去看看能找到些什么
Uh, I'll see what I can find.
不过首先 我得生火
But first, I'm gonna start a fire
让这个地方暖和起来
and get this place warmed up.
嘿 话说 Nick不在 对吗
Hey, um, Nick's not here, right?
我没看见他的车
I don't see his car.
呃 不在 据我所知他在工作啊
Uh, no, he's at work as far as I know.
你有试着打电话给他吗
Did you try calling him?
不 我不是想找他 我想找你谈谈
No, I don't want to talk to him, I want to talk to you.
你不会还是想回那辆拖车里去吧
You don't want to go back to the trailer, do you?
不 我是要和你谈谈这个
No, I want to talk about this.
嘿 这张照片很漂亮
Hey! That's a very nice photo.
没错吧 我说
Right? I think.
这是四年前拍的 而且我记得有关这张照片的一切
This was taken four years ago and I remember everything about it.
那就是她 名字叫做 Maureen Rodriguez
that's her. Meet Maureen Rodriguez.
而且在她名下的确有辆红色的78年的野马
And she does have a red '78 bronco registered in her name.
- 我们正在找那辆车  - 她是在哪里被发现的
- We're looking for it. - Where'd they find her?
距离第一个案发现场约两英里
About two Miles from where that ranch hand was killed and the cattle were mutilated.
她走在路中间
She was walking down the middle of the road,
想要拦车
trying to flag down cars.
她的确遇到了什么事情
So something did happen to her.
郡治安官对她的描述进行了调查
County sheriff checked out her story,
找到了她声称被带到的那个旧粮仓
found the old barn she said she was taken to.
有辆旅行车停在外面 引擎盖开着 车子坏了 没有车牌
Station wagon parked outside, hood up, broken down, no plates.
这可能就是我们要找的宇宙飞船哦
Which probably means that's our spaceship.
我们正在根据VIN (车辆识别号) 确定车主的身份
We're trying to I.D. The owner based on the VIN.
帮我个忙 查查那次牛被开膛破肚的事件
Do me a favor, look into these cattle mutilations.
从哪里开始 然后向哪个方向去了
Where they started, what direction they're going.
我们得赶在他之前
Gotta get ahead of this one.
我记得那晚发生的一切
I remembered everything about that night.
我们去的地方 我们做的事
Where we went, what we did when we were there,
那个吻
that kiss.
这是件好事啊
So that's a good thing.
Monroe 我想起我有多么爱他 我可以感受到这种爱
Monroe, I remembered how much I loved him.I could feel it.
这难道不是件好事儿吗
Then that's a really good thing, right?
不是吗 为什么不呢
Or no? Why not?
我是说难道这不是你想要的吗
I mean, isn't that what you wanted?
我曾经对他态度很恶劣 我怕我做的事情
I treated him so badly, I'm scared that what I've done
会让他不再爱我了
would just make it impossible for him to ever love me again.
听着 在这方面我不是个专家
Look, I'm not an expert in these things,
但关于你和Nick的事儿 我倒是
although when it comes to you and Nick, I'm certainly
比大多数人知道的清楚
privy to more than most...
我要告诉你的是 在我看来
But I just have to tell you, from what I've seen
过去这几星期中 没什么能表明
over the past several weeks, nothing suggests
他对你的爱有分毫的减少
that his core feelings for you have faded to any great degree.
我不是很肯定
I'm not so sure.
好吧 只有一个办法了
Well, there's only one way to know.
Juliette 你得告诉他这件事儿
Juliette, you have to tell him.
我想但是我很害怕
I want to but I'm scared.
怎么会 你们一起经历了这么多的事情
Come on, after all you've been through?
Monroe 这就是事实
Monroe, that's just it.
我不再是从前的我了
I'm not the same person that I once was
也许这就不是件好事儿
and maybe that is not such a good thing.
但我觉得还不错
Oh, I kind of think it is.
请别告诉Nick我们今天的谈话
Please just don't repeat any of this to Nick.
- 我找机会和他谈的  - 好的
- I'll talk to him when I'm ready. - All right.
我会尽力帮助你们的
I'll do anything I can to help.
现在就有件事情 也许你能帮我
There's one thing that might help.
说吧
Name it.
告诉我什么是格林
Tell me what a Grimm is.
什么 格林
A... a Grimm?
格林是一种能看见最黑暗世界的生物
A Grimm is someone who can see into the heart of darkness.
能看到其他人所不理解的事物
Someone who sees things other people don't understand.
- 我能看到一些  - 一些什么
- I can see things that... - That what?
大多数人看不到的事物
That most people can't.
那晚在房车里他说了些类似的话
He said something like that the night in the trailer.
就是他把我带到你家的那晚
The night that he brought me over to your house.
恩 我知道
Yeah, I know.
所以你究竟想告诉我什么
So what exactly are you trying to tell me?
我想告诉你 Nick是与众不同的
I'm trying to tell you he's different.
嗨 我拿到你要的残杀牲畜事件的统计了
Hey, I got the stats on the cattle mutilations you asked for.
有什么发现
And?
我把所报告的外星人攻击事件标了出来
I highlighted the reported ufo attacks.
看起来是两周前开始发生的
Seems to have started two weeks ago
在内布拉斯加州的林肯市 后来从那里向西北移动
in Lincoln, Nebraska, then moving northwest from there ever since.
可以看出攻击频率的变化趋势
You can see the frequency of attacks,
总共有27起 随着他们的移动不断上升
which total 27,increases as they travel.
关于牛和外星人的事儿你查的怎么样了
What is it about cows and aliens?
没查到什么
I got nothing.
- 怎么了  - 你找到他们了吗
- What? - Have you found them?
没有 不过快了 她马上就要生了
No. I'm close. She's ready to give birth soon.
当她分娩的时候 我会到场的
And when she does, I'll be there.
已经有四方在出价了
I've got four parties bidding now.
把他们三个一网打尽 我们就发财了
A set of three would be worth a fortune.
我正在努力的做 别再给我打电话了
Yeah, I'm working on it. Don't call me again.
事情做完我会给你打电话的
I'll call you when it's done.
我是Burkhardt
Burkhardt.
我拿着实验报告去找过你
Went by your desk with the lab report,
但你不在那儿
but you're not there.
有什么发现
What do you got?
在这场穿越全国的牲畜残杀神秘事件中
Something which finally sheds some real light on the mystery
终于发现了些线索
of the cattle mutilations across this country.
- 吴 你快点说  - 是卵巢
- While we're young, Wu. - Ovaries.
你再说一遍
Excuse me?
那人从牛身上拿走的东西
That's what was taken from the cows.
是它们的卵巢
Their ovaries.
- 明白了嘛  - 明白了
- Now you know. - Yes, I do.
什么回事
What?
难以置信
I don't believe this.
他们应该早就灭绝了
They were supposed to be extinct.
至少他们是这么告诉我的
At least that's what I was told.
这可不会出现在自然历史书里面
Well, that wouldn't exactly be in a natural history book.
不 这些生物有着不同寻常的历史
No, these things have a very unnatural history.
他们理应因狩猎而灭绝
They were supposedly hunted to extinction.
就像水牛一样 他们的皮肤价值连城
Like the buffalo, their skins were considered very valuable
因为其发光的特性
because of their luminescent quality.
他们被收藏家所收集  你真的看到了吗
They were hoarded by collectors. Did you actually see one?
没有
No.
不过有两个人说他们看到了外星人
But I've got two people who say that they've seen aliens.
我还找到了一片发光的皮肤
And I've got a piece of glowing skin
这种皮肤不知是人类的还是动物的
that can't be categorized as animal or human.
当我还小的时候 我们常常幻想他们是一种美丽的
When I was a kid, we used to think they were these
充满魔力的 会在黑暗中发光的生物
beautiful, magical creatures that would glow in the dark.
如果能看到一个这样的生物是非常幸运的
It was supposed to be really good luck to see one, you know,
就像小妖精的传说
like the leprechaun legend.
对农场主和惨死的牛来说就没那么幸运了
It wasn't so lucky for the ranch hand or the mutilated cows.
- 有牛惨死  - 是 有六头
- There were mutilated cows? - Yeah. Six of them.
其他农场上更多
More on other ranches.
给我一点时间 等一会儿
Give me just... wait, one second.
有什么东西被切除掉了吗
Was anything cut out of them?
它们的卵巢
Their ovaries.
这种生物不止一个并且她怀孕了
There's more than one and she's pregnant.
什么
What?
她靠自己打猎是绝对不可能的
There's no way she's doing the hunting on her own.
这么多卵巢是为了给她 这里 看
That's who the ovaries are for. Here, here, look.
萤光怪是一种古老的物种 其起源可以追溯到非洲
Gluhenvolk are an ancient wesen species with roots that go back to Africa.
怀孕的女性在孕期要食用牛的卵巢
The gestating female consumes cow ovaries during pregnancy.
我知道听着挺奇怪的 但对她们来说这就像
I know it sounds hinky, but let's just say
咸菜和冰激凌一样普通
it's their pickles and ice cream.
所以男性萤光怪杀牛只是为了得到它们的卵巢
So he is mutilating cows to get their ovaries
给孩子他妈吃
to feed to the mother of his soon-to-be-born child.
对牛的攻击频率越高
The closer the attack on cows are,
也就说明了她离分娩的时间越近
the closer she is to popping out a baby Gluhenvolk.
自从它们离开了内布拉斯加州以后 有27起攻击事件
There were 27 attacks since they left Nebraska.
27起 真的吗 她随时都有可能生下小孩
27? Seriously? She is gonna go into labor any minute.
Rosalee 你在吗
Rosalee?
- 喔 嗨 Nick  - 嗨
- Oh, hey, Nick. - Hey.
我看你们俩正翻书呢
Ah, I see you two have a book open there,
多半意味着有什么可怕的
which more likely than not portends
灾难发生了 反过来
some sort of catastrophic disaster, which in turn,
也意味着我和Rosalee的约会又要推迟了
can only mean my date with Rosalee has been put on hold.
Monroe 有一个萤光怪正到处杀牛取卵巢
Monroe, there is a Gluhenvolk mutilating cattle for ovaries
因为他妻子肚子里的孩子随时都可能出生
because he has a pregnant woman about to give birth any minute.
说真的
Seriously?
- 萤光怪  - 是的
- A Gluhenvolk? - Yes.
我还以为他们已经灭绝了
I thought they were extinct.
所以说他们正沿路返回
So they're moving along back roads
最后一次袭击牛是在这里
and the last cattle attack was right here.
车在这里被遗弃 那位女士被绑走
The car was abandoned here and the woman was abducted
就在这里的某个地方
somewhere along here.
如果她像我想的一样已经怀孕了
If she's as pregnant as I think she is,
她不能走太远  至少是在这种道路上不能
she can't get very far... not on those roads.
我猜 他们就在这里的某处
My guess, I'd say they're somewhere in here.
不是吗 一条路进 一条路出
Right? One road in, one road out.
她将会需要更多的卵巢
And she's going to need more ovaries.
我好像活在平行宇宙一样
I'm living in an alternate universe.
不 你只是对于你所处的宇宙更了解而已
No, you just have a better understanding of the one we're in.
好吧 我最好还是赶紧出发
Well, I'd better get out there.
Nick 我们想跟你一起去
Nick, we want to go with you.
这有可能是这个种族最后几个萤光怪了
This could be the last of a species, man.
如果可以 我们得去帮助他们
We need to help them if we can.
- 他也许杀过人  - 但孩子是无辜的
- He may have killed a guy. - But the baby is innocent.
我认得那辆车
I know that truck.
这车的主人一直在跟着萤光怪
This guy's been following our Gluhenvolk.
为什么
Why?
他是个不明飞行物研究学家
He's a ufologist.
他也许已经找到他们了 我得进去看看
He may have found them and I gotta find out.
哇 哇 你等会儿
Whoa, whoa, hold on.
他可能在里边正睡着呢
He might be asleep in there, man.
你难道不需要个搜查令吗
Don't you need a warrant for that?
你说得对 还是你来开吧
You're right. You open it.
喔 行吧
Oh, okay.
有人吗
Hello?
这是把削肉刀
This is a fleshing knife.
噢 我觉得他不是个不明飞行物研究者
Um, I don't think this guy's a ufologist.
Sauver sa peau (法语引申为逃命或保全性命)
Sauver sa peau.
"留下你的皮"
"Save your skin"?
就是字面上的意思
Must mean literally.
如果你把这个东西装入子弹射中一个格林生物的话
If you shot a wesen with this stuff in that bullet...
会要了他的命 知道吗
the bullet would kill him, okay?
但是这个sauver sa peau会将他皮肤保持变身时的状态
But the sauver sa peau would keep him in full woge,
甚至在死后也是一样
even after death.
- 永久不变  - 不
- Forever? - No.
是暂时的
This is just temporary.
大概过六或八个小时
You probably have no more than six or eight hours
就变回人类
before you would change back.
所以他不得不迅速地割下皮然后晒干
So he has to harvest and tan the hides very quickly.
这里就是他的操作室
He does it right here in his trailer.
这个太过分了
This is so wrong.
但这会让人拥有一个完美 已变身的标本用作出售
But you would have a perfectly morphed specimen to sell.
我们最好在那个人之前找到那些萤光怪
We'd better find those Gluhenvolk before he does.
怎么找
How?
他们正开着一辆偷来的野马牌汽车
They're driving a stolen bronco,
我们在路上没有看到任何一辆
we didn't pass one on the road,
这里也没有地方掉头
and there was no place to turn off.
他们一定在我们前面的某处
They've got to be ahead of us somewhere.
我来拿这些
I'm taking these.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
- 你为什么停下了  - Nick你看到了什么吗
- Why are you stopping? - Nick, do you see something?
我好像看到了一栋房子
I think I see a building.
有人在这里转弯了
Somebody turned off here.
闸门被弄倒了
The gate's down.
有人在这儿生火了
Somebody's got a fire going.
你闻到没
You smell that?
这里只有一道轮胎的印儿
There's only one set of tracks.
有人进去了 但没有出来
Somebody went in and didn't come out.
我们去瞧瞧
Let's check it.
Vincent 是你吗
Vincent?
靠  没打中
Damn it.
噢 我的天哪 离我远点
Oh, my God. Oh, get away from me.
请你放轻松 好吗
Please, just take it easy, okay?
我们不会伤害你的 我们是来帮你的
We're not gonna hurt you. We're here to help.
Vincent在哪里 你们对他做了什么
Where's Vincent? What have you done with him?
你需要告诉我们他在哪里
We need you to tell us where he is.
别伤害我
Don't hurt me.
- 噢 老天爷  - 别伤害我的宝贝
- Oh, my God. - Don't hurt my baby.
原来这是真的
It's true.
喔 你真漂亮
Oh, you're beautiful.
离我远点 离我
Stay away from me! Stay awa...
啊 好疼
aah!
我想她马上要分娩了
I think she's going into labor.
Nick 我觉得你给她太大压力了
Whoa, Nick, I think you put her over the top.
我们需要很多东西 可是这里什么也没有
We're gonna need a bunch of stuff we don't have.
喔 孩子要出来了 孩子要出来了
Oh, the baby's coming. The baby's coming.
我们完全不会伤害你 我们是来帮助你的
We're not gonna hurt you at all, we're here to help you.
你需要躺在地上
You need to roll onto your back.
喔 老天爷 她的羊水刚刚破了
Oh, my God, her water just broke.
- 我们还有多少时间  - 一点也没有
- How much time do we have? - Like, none.
在车里有急救药箱
I've got a first aid kit in my car.
保持呼吸  扶住她的头
Keep breathing. Hold her head.
现在把你的腿慢慢伸展开来 好吗
We're gonna have to spread your legs, okay?
这里 抓着我的手
Here, now just take hold of my hand.
我们一定会成功的
We'll get through this.
我需要酒精擦手
I need alcohol wipes for my hands.
- 啊 疼  - Monroe
- Ow, ow, ow, ow. - Monroe!
她快要把我手弄断了
She's, like, breaking my hand.
- 我做不到  - 你做的很好了
- I can't do this. - You're doing just fine.
- 我做不到  - 你做的非常好了
- I can't do this. - You're doing just great.
你做的好极了 保持呼吸
You're doing great, keep breathing.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫Jocelyn  痛
Jocelyn... oh!
好 Jocelyn 我叫Rosalee
Okay, jocelyn, my name's Rosalee.
这是Monroe 那是Nick
This is Monroe and that's Nick.
- 很高兴见到你  - 孩子快出来了
- Nice to meet you. - The baby's crowning.
Nick 我需要你用手压她的腰背部
Nick, I'm gonna need you to put counter-pressure with your hands on the small of her back.
- 好的  - 好的
- Okay. - Okay.
好 Jocelyn 要开始使劲儿了
All right, jocelyn, we're gonna push.
要开始使劲儿了 准备好
We're gonna push, okay?
好 继续使劲儿 干得好 使劲儿
All right, keep pushing. Here we go. Push.
加油 使劲儿 Jocelyn 你做的很好
There you go. Push, jocelyn, there you go.
Jocelyn你怎么样
Jocelyn?
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
- 发生了什么  - 孩子马上生下来了
- What's going on? - The baby's coming.
我们呃在帮忙 赶紧过来搭把手
We're, uh, helping, so just join in anytime.
- Vincent Vincent  - 嗯 我在这儿  我在这儿
- Vincent! Vincent! - Yeah, I'm here, I'm here.
继续使劲儿 继续使劲儿
Keep pushing. Keep pushing.
好 快要生出来了 快来了
All right, it's coming. Here it comes.
出来了
It's coming.
孩子出来了
I've got the baby.
给你
There you go.
喔 你做到了
Oh, you did it.
Monroe 你能把毯子拿过来吗
Monroe, will you grab the blanket?
- 毯子  - 在那里
- Blanket. - Right there.
噢 这里
Oh, here, here, here.
孩子真漂亮
It's beautiful.
我们有女儿了
We have a daughter.
是啊 我们有了
Yes, we do.
一个其乐融融的三口之家
One big, happy family.
我只拿我想要的东西
All I want is what I came for.
你们不会受伤 除非你们不知好歹
You don't have to get hurt unless you want to.
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
那我呢 我值多少钱
What about me? What am I worth?
喔 不止一个狼人
Ooh, more than a Blutbad.
那我这个格林呢
What about a Grimm?
你能值多少
How much are you worth?
- 我们做到了  - 没事儿了
- We did it. - It's okay.
- 我们该拿他们怎么办  - 那他呢
- What do we do with them? - What do we do with him?
我们得带着他们离开这里
We gotta get them out of here.
走吧 离这里越远越好
Just get as far away from here as you can.
感谢你们为我们做的一切
Thanks for everything you guys did for us.
你们要去哪儿
Where you headed?
在阿拉斯加还有一些残留的族人
There's a few of us left... In Alaska.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
还有不要再杀牛了
And no more cows, guys.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
你觉得他们找到了那个人了吗
You think they found that guy?
应该快了
Should be there soon.
希望在药剂失效前被发现
Hopefully before the drugs wear off.
掩护右边
Cover right.
举起手来 立刻举起手来
Hands up! Get your hands up now!
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
我们发现它了 发现外星人了
We got it, we got the alien.
好 所有人往后退
All right, everybody step back.
后退
Move back.
做好应对一切的准备
Be prepared for anything here now.
== 格林 第二季第19集 ==
【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献
== 翻译&时间轴：云云 暮暮 特特 校对：天之行者 蜜蜜==
== 统筹：尧之雪 后期：飞在果壳里 封装：BG-Sandman ==
本字幕仅用于学习交流之用
禁止用于任何商业用途 否则后果自负
【H-SGDK】字幕组欢迎各位加入
有意者请加QQ群109164858，注明 字幕组+申请职位即可
== 格林 第二季第19集 完 ==
【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献